Want a convenient and secure way
to access your Government of Canada services and benefits?
Register for My Service Canada Account today!
This account gives you secure access to services and benefits
related to the Canada Pension Plan,
Old Age Security and Employment Insurance.
You can also sign up for direct deposit
to have your payments sent directly to your bank account.
To register, you’ll need to provide some personal information,
including your date of birth and Social Insurance Number.
For safety and security, you will need to validate your identity
with a personal access code
or by using the Interac® verification service.
Don’t have a personal access code?
Don’t worry, you can request one online,
by phone or at a Service Canada Centre.
The Interac® verification service
will allow you to register for My Service Canada Account
safely and instantly by using your online
banking information.
To put your mind at ease, we have added multi-factor
authentication to help protect your account!
Once registered, there are three ways to sign in.
You can sign in with your GCKey, with a sign-in partner,
such as your bank,
or with your provincial digital ID
if you live in British Columbia or Alberta.
Each one of the three sign-in options is safe and secure!
And you can do it all from your computer, phone or tablet.
Register now to see all the advantages
My Service Canada Account has to offer!
Visit canada.ca/MyServiceCanadaAccount to register.