<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"
                 href="http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst?max-results=5&amp;q=pingo&amp;alt=rss"/>
      <atom:link rel="next" type="application/rss+xml"
                 href="http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst?start-index=808032&amp;max-results=5&amp;q=pingo&amp;alt=rss"/>
      <title>GeoGratis Product Selection</title>
      <description>Natural Resources Canada</description>
      <link>http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst?max-results=5&amp;q=pingo</link>
      <language>en</language>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 11:23:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 11:23:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <managingEditor>info@geogratis.gc.ca (GeoGratis)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>info@geogratis.gc.ca (GeoGratis)</webMaster>
      <docs>http://geogratis.gc.ca</docs>
      <item>
         <title>An assessment of surficial geology, massive ice, and ground ice, Tuktoyaktuk Peninsula, Northwest Territories: application to the proposed Inuvik to Tuktoyaktuk all-weather highway</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>This report utilizes seismic shothole drillers' lithostratigraphic logs as a basis for contrasting previously published maps and reports of surficial geology, massive ice and ground ice, on the Tuktoyaktuk Peninsula, Northwest Territories. Areas of glaciofluvial ice-contact and outwash deposits, and lacustrine sediments in thermokarst terrain are demonstrated to be less extensive, while areas of till cover are more widespread. Approximately 2% of all shotholes contain records of massive ice, it is most abundant between 4 and 14 m depth, and principally is situated at lithostratigraphic contacts (73%). On the Tuktoyaktuk Peninsula, half (52%) of the massive ice records occur in areas of surface till cover, and it is largely underlain by "sorted + sorted, fine" deposits (72%). Significant spatial, lithostratigraphic, and thickness differences are noted in other physiographic regions. Shothole ground ice records are more common (13% of all such records), particularly within the 15
km buffer area surrounding the proposed Inuvik to Tuktoyaktuk Highway (18.4%), although it is acknowledged that many such records may relate to massive ice deposits, and that drillers typically under-report ground ice occurrence. There is significant disagreement between shothole-based massive ice and ground ice occurrences with existing permafrost and ground ice maps that were constructed on the basis of surficial geology-related ground ice associations. Changes in surficial geology classification account for part, elsewhere, ground ice is simply found to be more abundant in different deposit types than previously surmised.
It is argued that integration of abundant shothole lithostratigraphic data provides a more reliable reconstruction of surficial geology, massive ice, and ground ice conditions in the Tuktoyaktuk Peninsula. The data and syntheses presented can better inform engineering and landscape stability assessments, and similarly identify areas wherein more detailed field-surveys and inspection are likely required as part of an infrastructure development proposal.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst/dbd76aad-0f71-508d-91f3-0bca79af2dd4.html</link>
         <author>info@geogratis.gc.ca (GeoGratis)</author>
         <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 05:01:38 GMT</pubDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst/dbd76aad-0f71-508d-91f3-0bca79af2dd4.xml</guid>
         <georss:polygon>68.25 -134 69.5 -134 69.5 -132.5 68.25 -132.5 68.25 -134</georss:polygon>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Surficial Geology, Inman River, District of Mackenzie, Northwest Territories</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Abstract not available.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst/fe2f6bfa-adbc-5a3e-ade8-0d416dbb2bed.html</link>
         <author>info@geogratis.gc.ca (GeoGratis)</author>
         <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:44:49 GMT</pubDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst/fe2f6bfa-adbc-5a3e-ade8-0d416dbb2bed.xml</guid>
         <georss:polygon>68 -120 69.416700000000006 -120 69.416700000000006 -113.75 68 -113.75 68 -120</georss:polygon>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Surficial Geology, Tuktoyaktuk Coastlands, District of Mackenzie, Northwest Territories</title>
         <description><![CDATA[<p>Abstract not available.</p>]]></description>
         <link>http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst/5995a4b8-f36f-5cc9-a48a-44cc82edb068.html</link>
         <author>info@geogratis.gc.ca (GeoGratis)</author>
         <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 02:11:55 GMT</pubDate>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://geogratis.gc.ca/api/en/nrcan-rncan/ess-sst/5995a4b8-f36f-5cc9-a48a-44cc82edb068.xml</guid>
         <georss:polygon>68 -136 70.666700000000006 -136 70.666700000000006 -126.5 68 -126.5 68 -136</georss:polygon>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>